<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ens on LearnOverpass</title>
    <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ens on LearnOverpass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>That&#39;s all for now!</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great work! That&amp;rsquo;s all for now. Check back again later and thanks for coming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Question #2</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great work. Here&amp;rsquo;s a last one. Can you count how many museums there are in New York City per borough?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Question #1</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow! That was great work so far. Let&amp;rsquo;s recap what we&amp;rsquo;ve learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query within areas using bounding boxes, &lt;code&gt;(around:n)&lt;/code&gt;, and areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filter by &lt;code&gt;[key=value]&lt;/code&gt; tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use regular expressions to find non-exact tag values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query for nodes, ways, and relations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chain together multiple query statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Union multiple query statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the output format of results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a for loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow. That was a lot. Challenge Question time! Can you find all the schools and parks in New York City that are within 50 meters of each other?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreach Loops</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 17:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wonderful! You found 471 bikeshares in Boston and New York City. Now, hold on to your hats, because we&amp;rsquo;re going to introduce a whole bunch of concepts here. We&amp;rsquo;re going to count the number of Citi Bike stations in each New York City county. For this, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to use a new function &lt;code&gt;map_to_area&lt;/code&gt;, look for relations, and create a &lt;code&gt;foreach&lt;/code&gt; loop. For good measure, we&amp;rsquo;ll also output the results as a csv!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 12:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;ndash; we found all the bike shares that are Citi Bike or Hubway in Boston and New York City. You&amp;rsquo;ll notice that some bike stations are missing. Obviously, the new stations that have been installed recently haven&amp;rsquo;t been added yet, or they may have been tagged differently. Feel free to check out &lt;code&gt;out meta&lt;/code&gt; to see when this dataset was last updated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unions!</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Awesome! We now have a decent map of where CARTO is. We have a chain of queries using different search area methods. There are three outputs -the cafes, CARTO Brooklyn, and Bushwick Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s leave Sally because we think she can find her way to CARTO now. Let&amp;rsquo;s build a query to look for bicycle rental nodes in both Boston and New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to learn how to group statements together.
A &lt;strong&gt;union&lt;/strong&gt; allows you to group the results of several queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(statement_1; statement_2; …)-&amp;gt;.result_set;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and is written as a pair of parentheses. Inside the union, any sequence of statements can be placed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Area</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So there are quite a few Bushwick Avenues in the world. It looks like there&amp;rsquo;s at least three in Long Island and even one in New Jersey. Let&amp;rsquo;s limit the search area to just New York City. Areas are kind of funny in OSM. You can read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;http://michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/docs/filters/area/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve learned limit the search search  with a bounding box and an &amp;ldquo;around&amp;rdquo; filter already, but now we will use an area filter. First, we need to find areas with the name &amp;ldquo;New York City&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads to Nowhere</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hooray! You found CARTO Brooklyn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like Sally needs to walk down Bushwick Avenue to get here. Let&amp;rsquo;s put that on the Overpass map for her too. You should know all the steps to find and visualize a street (aka way) named &amp;lsquo;Bushwick Avenue&amp;rsquo; by now!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is the Way?</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I still don&amp;rsquo;t know where I need to go!&amp;rdquo; Sally wails. Why is there still no CARTO in Brooklyn? Sally is very sure this building should exist. And so do we because we&amp;rsquo;re sitting inside it right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &amp;ldquo;Data&amp;rdquo; view of our results right now. We see the three cafe nodes printed out (Dun-Well Doughnuts, Jessie&amp;rsquo;s Bakery, and Bread Brothers). But what about the way? It looks like a list of node ids. We need to change the output method to get these points on the map!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sally Goes to Spain???</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Huh&amp;hellip; so it looks like CARTO is in Madrid! Sally is very worried that she misread the MeetUp and accidentally went to CARTO Brooklyn instead of CARTO Madrid. But wait! This is where we learn that there are things other than &lt;strong&gt;nodes&lt;/strong&gt; that exist in OpenStreetMap. Obviously, there are polygons and lines too! In OSM-speak, these are called &lt;strong&gt;ways&lt;/strong&gt;. A way is essentially an ordered list of nodes that make up linear features like roads, rivers, etc. A closed way (where the first and last node is the same) is a polygon and can represent building footprints, parks, regions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, OSM has &lt;strong&gt;relations&lt;/strong&gt; which is a data structure describing a relationship. For example, if you have a building with a hole in it (like a courtyard), a single &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; can&amp;rsquo;t represent this. A relation that represents this complex multipolygon needs to be used instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucky for us, CARTO Brooklyn is a pretty regular looking rectangular building. Let&amp;rsquo;s look for a &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; with the name CARTO!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donuts to CARTO!</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great, you found three cafes! Sally heads into Dunwell Doughnuts to end the rumblings in her stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s recap what we&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query for nodes (aka points) in areas using both bounding boxes and &lt;code&gt;(around:n)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filter by &lt;code&gt;[key=value]&lt;/code&gt; tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use regular expressions to find non-exact tag values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chain together multiple query statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s now time we figured out where CARTO is!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around and Around We Go!</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice! It looks like Sally is standing by the Citibike station outside the Montrose (L) station. Sally is really late for CartoCamp, but now she says she&amp;rsquo;s getting a hungry and could use a snack&amp;hellip; Can you help her find a cafe nearby? She&amp;rsquo;s feeling pretty lazy too, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to walk far! What are her options?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around and Around We Go!</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh no, nothing was found! Is Sally wrong? She says she definitely sees a Citibike station. It turns out that we can&amp;rsquo;t put these filter statements together because we&amp;rsquo;re not looking for a node that is tagged as both a railway station AND a Citibike station. We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a second node that is &lt;strong&gt;around&lt;/strong&gt; the first one. In Overpass, queries are chained together &amp;ndash; output from a first query will flow as input into the next query.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, we queried for nodes in an &lt;em&gt;area&lt;/em&gt; (the bounding box). Now, we&amp;rsquo;re going to look for nodes within a new area &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; the two nodes we found. Let&amp;rsquo;s use the Overpass function &lt;strong&gt;around&lt;/strong&gt; to search for Citibike stations nearby Montrose and Morgan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around and Around We Go!</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great! We&amp;rsquo;ve narrowed it down to two subway stations&amp;ndash; Montrose and Morgan stations. Sally just texted us again and she says she sees a Citibike station nearby. Another clue!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regex to the Rescue!</title>
      <link>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 16:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//michellemho.github.io/learnoverpass/en/exercises/intro/3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay! We found a few subway stations that Sally might be at. And Sally just remembered that the name of the subway stop started with &amp;ldquo;Mo&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; but she can&amp;rsquo;t remember the rest. Oh, Sally! Can we use this information to help figure out which station Sally is at? Let&amp;rsquo;s find names of nodes that start with the letters &amp;ldquo;Mo&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overpass supports a form of &lt;strong&gt;regular expressions&lt;/strong&gt; that can help us search for non-exact tag values. Let&amp;rsquo;s use &lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; in a filter statement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>